[
	{
		"answerText": "Pyrenees Mountains [or Pirineos; or Pyrénées; or Perinés; or Pirineus; or Pirenèus; or Pirinioak; or Auñamendiak][10] This mountain range runs the length of the Italian peninsula and is home to the rapidly-shrinking Calderone glacier. The small nation of San Marino is located around Monte Titano in this range.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "BELLOCO |2014 | 4 | 10 | Geography | None | HS",
		"subject": "Geography",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: Name some European mountain ranges. [10] This mountain range divides France from Spain. The tiny nation of Andorra lies in these mountains, which run from the Bay of Biscay to the Cap de Creus.",
		"answers": [
			"Pyrenees",
			"Mountains",
			"Pirineos",
			"Pyrénées",
			"Perinés",
			"Pirineus",
			"Pirenèus",
			"Pirinioak",
			"Auñamendiak",
			"10",
			"This",
			"mountain",
			"range",
			"runs",
			"length",
			"Italian",
			"peninsula",
			"and",
			"home",
			"to",
			"rapidly-shrinking",
			"Calderone",
			"glacier",
			"The",
			"small",
			"nation",
			"San",
			"Marino",
			"located",
			"around",
			"Monte",
			"Titano",
			"in",
			"this"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Mississippi River[10] This lake in Minnesota is often cited as the source of the main length of the Mississippi River.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Masonic |2014 | 7 | 1 | Geography | None | HS",
		"subject": "Geography",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10] Name this longest river in the United States. Its major tributaries include the Ohio and Missouri.",
		"answers": [
			"Mississippi",
			"River",
			"10",
			"This",
			"lake",
			"in",
			"Minnesota",
			"often",
			"cited",
			"as",
			"source",
			"main",
			"length"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Hawaii Island[10] This most populous of the Hawaiian islands is the home of Honolulu.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Masonic |2014 | 7 | 2 | Geography | None | HS",
		"subject": "Geography",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10] Name this largest of James Cook's \"Sandwich Islands.\"",
		"answers": [
			"Hawaii",
			"Island",
			"10",
			"This",
			"most",
			"populous",
			"Hawaiian",
			"islands",
			"home",
			"Honolulu"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Lesser Antilles [prompt on Antilles] [10] The Lesser Antilles can be found in this sea. Europeans called islands in this sea the West Indies",
		"prompts": [
			"Antilles",
			"10",
			"The",
			"Lesser",
			"Antilles",
			"can",
			"be",
			"found",
			"in",
			"this",
			"sea",
			"Europeans",
			"called",
			"islands",
			"in",
			"this",
			"sea",
			"West",
			"Indies"
		],
		"heading": "NASAT  |2014 | 20 | 19 | Geography | None | HS",
		"subject": "Geography",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: One member of this chain of islands is a lifeless rock named Redonda whose second-to-last king \"Robert the Bald\" was succeeded by \"Michael the Grey\" in 2009. For 10 points each:  [10] Redonda, which belongs to Antigua and Barbuda, is a member of the Leeward Islands, which makes up this island chain along with the Windward Islands. ",
		"answers": [
			"Lesser",
			"Antilles"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "French Indochina[10] Led by the Chakri dynasty, this country was the only Southeast Asian country to escape colonization. It lost Laos and the Malay peninsula to the French and British, respectively, and retains its monarchy today.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2014 | 01 | 13 | Geography | None | HS",
		"subject": "Geography",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: For 10 points each, name the following about Southeast Asia during the colonial period. [10] This French colony included the present-day countries of Vietnam, Laos, and Cambodia. These countries became independent in 1954, following the Geneva accords, despite French military intervention.",
		"answers": [
			"French",
			"Indochina",
			"10",
			"Led",
			"by",
			"Chakri",
			"dynasty",
			"this",
			"country",
			"was",
			"only",
			"Southeast",
			"Asian",
			"to",
			"escape",
			"colonization",
			"It",
			"lost",
			"Laos",
			"and",
			"Malay",
			"peninsula",
			"British",
			"respectively",
			"retains",
			"its",
			"monarchy",
			"today"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Nova Scotia[10] Nova Scotia is bordered to the west by this body of water, which has access to the Irving oil refinery and is located on a rift valley. St John's lies on it, and it separates most of New Brunswick from Nova Scotia.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2014 | 02 | 17 | Geography | None | HS",
		"subject": "Geography",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: Answer these questions about the maritime provinces, for 10 points each: [10] This province includes the traditionally-Scottish-inhabited Cape Breton Island, although its capital, Halifax, is on the mainland. French settlers from Acadia were deported from this place and it was renamed by the Brits in 1755.",
		"answers": [
			"Nova",
			"Scotia",
			"10",
			"bordered",
			"to",
			"west",
			"by",
			"this",
			"body",
			"water",
			"which",
			"has",
			"access",
			"Irving",
			"oil",
			"refinery",
			"and",
			"located",
			"rift",
			"valley",
			"St",
			"John's",
			"lies",
			"separates",
			"most",
			"New",
			"Brunswick",
			"from"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Berlin[10] To the southeast of Berlin is this capital of the state of Brandenburg that once served as the official seat of the Kaiser. A namesake declaration from this city called for Japan's unconditional surrender.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2014 | 04 | 20 | Geography | None | HS",
		"subject": "Geography",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: Its borough of Steglitz-Zehlendorf contains two bodies of water known as the greater and lesser Wannsees. For 10 points each: [10] Name this German capital city that contains the locality of Spandau and the Brandenburg Gate.",
		"answers": [
			"Berlin",
			"10",
			"To",
			"southeast",
			"this",
			"capital",
			"state",
			"Brandenburg",
			"that",
			"once",
			"served",
			"as",
			"official",
			"seat",
			"Kaiser",
			"A",
			"namesake",
			"declaration",
			"from",
			"city",
			"called",
			"for",
			"Japan's",
			"unconditional",
			"surrender"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Connecticut River[10] The Connecticut River passes just west of this capital city of Connecticut.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "BISB |2013 | 2 | 11 | Geography | None | HS",
		"subject": "Geography",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: The so-called \"Great Attack\" occurred on this river during the War of 1812. For 10 points each: [10] Name this river which forms the border between New Hampshire and Vermont and reaches its terminus near Saybrook. It's the longest river in New England.",
		"answers": [
			"Connecticut",
			"River",
			"10",
			"The",
			"passes",
			"just",
			"west",
			"this",
			"capital",
			"city"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Great Bear Lake[10] The Great Bear Lake is located southwest of Nunavut in this Canadian territory. Settlements here include Inuvik and Hay River.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "GSAC |2013 | 1 | 6 | Geography | None | HS",
		"subject": "Geography",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: Uranium mining near this body of water has caused controversy and the town of Deline lies on its western shore. For 10 points each: [10] Name this lake, the largest located entirely within Canada.",
		"answers": [
			"Great",
			"Bear",
			"Lake",
			"10",
			"The",
			"located",
			"southwest",
			"Nunavut",
			"in",
			"this",
			"Canadian",
			"territory",
			"Settlements",
			"here",
			"include",
			"Inuvik",
			"and",
			"Hay",
			"River"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Rio de la Plata[10] Sites in this capital city on one shore of the Rio de la Plata include the Prado and Rodo Parks and the Palacio Salvo.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "GSAC |2013 | 5 | 6 | Geography | None | HS",
		"subject": "Geography",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: Name some things related to a river in South America, for 10 points each: [10] This estuary is formed by the confluence of the Paraná and Uruguay Rivers.",
		"answers": [
			"Rio",
			"de",
			"la",
			"Plata",
			"10",
			"Sites",
			"in",
			"this",
			"capital",
			"city",
			"one",
			"shore",
			"include",
			"Prado",
			"and",
			"Rodo",
			"Parks",
			"Palacio",
			"Salvo"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Bermuda[10] This other British Overseas territory located north of its namesake strait, is famous for its rock and monkeys, but is also a source of conflict between the UK and Spain.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "GSAC |2013 | 7 | 11 | Geography | None | HS",
		"subject": "Geography",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: Located 650 miles off Cape Hatteras, islands in this archipelago include Somerset Island and St. George's Island. For 10 points each: [10] Name this British Overseas Territory whose capital is Hamilton.",
		"answers": [
			"Bermuda",
			"10",
			"This",
			"other",
			"British",
			"Overseas",
			"territory",
			"located",
			"north",
			"its",
			"namesake",
			"strait",
			"famous",
			"for",
			"rock",
			"and",
			"monkeys",
			"but",
			"also",
			"source",
			"conflict",
			"between",
			"UK",
			"Spain"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Yellowstone National Park[10] This geyser in Yellowstone, named in 1870 for its predicability, erupts approximately every 91 minutes.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "James |2013 | 1 | 10 | Geography | None | HS",
		"subject": "Geography",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: The Roosevelt Arch lies at this park's northern entrance. For 10 points each:  [10] Name this national park, the first in the United States.",
		"answers": [
			"Yellowstone",
			"National",
			"Park",
			"10",
			"This",
			"geyser",
			"in",
			"named",
			"1870",
			"for",
			"its",
			"predicability",
			"erupts",
			"approximately",
			"every",
			"91",
			"minutes"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "New York City[10] This river is connected to the Hudson via the Spuyten Duyvil [Spooi-ten Dooi-vil] Creek. It forms the northern boundary of Manhattan, and is crossed by Interstate 278 over the Triborough Bridge.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "James |2013 | 10 | 17 | Geography | None | HS",
		"subject": "Geography",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: Although not the capital, this is the largest city in the state of the same name. For 10 points each: [10] Name this largest city of the United States, consisting of five boroughs.",
		"answers": [
			"New",
			"York",
			"City",
			"10",
			"This",
			"river",
			"connected",
			"to",
			"Hudson",
			"via",
			"Spuyten",
			"Duyvil",
			"Spooi-ten",
			"Dooi-vil",
			"Creek",
			"It",
			"forms",
			"northern",
			"boundary",
			"Manhattan",
			"and",
			"crossed",
			"by",
			"Interstate",
			"278",
			"over",
			"Triborough",
			"Bridge"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Dubai[10] In addition to The World Islands and The Universe Islands, Nakheel Properties developed these three artificial archipelagoes named Jebel Ali, Jumeirah, and Deira, which remain under construction. They are located off the coast of Dubai.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "James |2013 | 11 | 9 | Geography | None | HS",
		"subject": "Geography",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: This city is home to the the tallest building in the world, the Burj Khalifa, which was formerly named after the city. For 10 points each: [10] Name this city on the Persian Gulf, one of the seven United Arab Emirates.",
		"answers": [
			"Dubai",
			"10",
			"In",
			"addition",
			"to",
			"The",
			"World",
			"Islands",
			"and",
			"Universe",
			"Nakheel",
			"Properties",
			"developed",
			"these",
			"three",
			"artificial",
			"archipelagoes",
			"named",
			"Jebel",
			"Ali",
			"Jumeirah",
			"Deira",
			"which",
			"remain",
			"under",
			"construction",
			"They",
			"are",
			"located",
			"off",
			"coast"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Vietnam War[10] The Vietnam Veterans Memorial was designed by this architect who received criticism for her Asian ethnicity. This architect also designed a Civil Rights Memorial in Montgomery, Alabama.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "James |2013 | 11 | 19 | Geography | None | HS",
		"subject": "Geography",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: A Moving Wall version of a structure honoring veterans of this war travels across the country. For 10 points each: [10] Give this war whose veterans are honored by two reflective black gabbro walls inscribed with the names of the killed-in-action and missing-in-action of this war.",
		"answers": [
			"Vietnam",
			"War",
			"10",
			"The",
			"Veterans",
			"Memorial",
			"was",
			"designed",
			"by",
			"this",
			"architect",
			"who",
			"received",
			"criticism",
			"for",
			"her",
			"Asian",
			"ethnicity",
			"This",
			"also",
			"Civil",
			"Rights",
			"in",
			"Montgomery",
			"Alabama"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Massachusetts [10] This only national park in Maine contains the Somes Sound and much of Mount Desert Island.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "James |2013 | 12 | 6 | Geography | None | HS",
		"subject": "Geography",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: New England is composed of six states. For 10 points each: [10] Name this state, with capital Boston, that is home to Harvard University.",
		"answers": [
			"Massachusetts",
			"10",
			"This",
			"only",
			"national",
			"park",
			"in",
			"Maine",
			"contains",
			"Somes",
			"Sound",
			"and",
			"much",
			"Mount",
			"Desert",
			"Island"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Vatican City or the Holy See [10] This nation, whose most populous quartier is Monte Carlo, is located in the French Riviera.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "James |2013 | 13 | 11 | Geography | None | HS",
		"subject": "Geography",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: Europe is the smallest continent and is thus home to some really tiny countries. For 10 points each: [10] Name this nation, the smallest in the world. It is home to the headquarters of the Roman Catholic Church, leading to the amusing statistic of having six popes per square mile.  ",
		"answers": [
			"Vatican",
			"City",
			"Holy",
			"See",
			"10",
			"This",
			"nation",
			"whose",
			"most",
			"populous",
			"quartier",
			"Monte",
			"Carlo",
			"located",
			"in",
			"French",
			"Riviera"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Cape Horn[10] Cape Horn lies on this archipelago shared between Argentina and Chile. It's name in Spanish literally means \"land of fire.\"",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "James |2013 | 14 | 3 | Geography | None | HS",
		"subject": "Geography",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: Going around this point means traversing the Drake Passage; two shortcuts are the Beagle Channel and the better known Strait of Magellan. For 10 points each: [10] Name this cape, the southern most point of South America.",
		"answers": [
			"Cape",
			"Horn",
			"10",
			"lies",
			"this",
			"archipelago",
			"shared",
			"between",
			"Argentina",
			"and",
			"Chile",
			"It's",
			"name",
			"in",
			"Spanish",
			"literally",
			"means",
			"land",
			"fire"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "France (or French Republic)[10] This peak, the highest in Europe outside of Russia, is located on the border of Rhone-Alpes and the Italian region of Aosta Valley.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "James |2013 | 14 | 22 | Geography | None | HS",
		"subject": "Geography",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: This western European nation has 27 regions including Alsace, Lorraine, and Corsica. For 10 points each: [10] The Eiffel Tower is located in this country whose capital is located in a landlocked region named \"island of this nation\" when literally translated.",
		"answers": [
			"France",
			"French",
			"Republic",
			"10",
			"This",
			"peak",
			"highest",
			"in",
			"Europe",
			"outside",
			"Russia",
			"located",
			"border",
			"Rhone-Alpes",
			"and",
			"Italian",
			"region",
			"Aosta",
			"Valley"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Nile River[10] Third in length to the Nile and Congo, this West African river is the namesake of two of the countries it flows through. It was the principal river of the Mali, Ghana, and Songhay Empires.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "James |2013 | 2 | 14 | Geography | None | HS",
		"subject": "Geography",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: The Aswan High Dam lies on this river. For 10 points each:  [10] Name this longest African river whose Blue and White varieties meet at Khartoum. The distinctive shape of this river's mouth on the Mediterranean is the origin of the term 'delta.'",
		"answers": [
			"Nile",
			"River",
			"10",
			"Third",
			"in",
			"length",
			"to",
			"and",
			"Congo",
			"this",
			"West",
			"African",
			"river",
			"namesake",
			"two",
			"countries",
			"flows",
			"through",
			"It",
			"was",
			"principal",
			"Mali",
			"Ghana",
			"Songhay",
			"Empires"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Berlin[10] This city is located in Germany's southeast. It is the capital of the state of Bavaria and is the home of BMW.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "James |2013 | 3 | 2 | Geography | None | HS",
		"subject": "Geography",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: Germany is the most populous nation in the European Union, and many of those people happen to live in cities. Name some German cities, for 10 points each: [10] This city is the capital of Germany and was divided by a wall for much of the later half of the 20th century. ",
		"answers": [
			"Berlin",
			"10",
			"This",
			"city",
			"located",
			"in",
			"Germany's",
			"southeast",
			"It",
			"capital",
			"state",
			"Bavaria",
			"and",
			"home",
			"BMW"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Ontario[10] This province borders Ontario to the west and includes the city of Winnipeg.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "James |2013 | 4 | 7 | Geography | None | HS",
		"subject": "Geography",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: Though many uninformed people believe that Canada is one of the 51 United States of America, it is in fact its own nation with its own subdivisions, provinces and territories. For 10 points each: [10] Name this province which is the largest by population and includes the cities of Toronto and Ottawa.",
		"answers": [
			"Ontario",
			"10",
			"This",
			"province",
			"borders",
			"to",
			"west",
			"and",
			"includes",
			"city",
			"Winnipeg"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "the South [accept equivalents][10] This Texas metropolitan region, an American Airlines hub, is the largest in the South.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "James |2013 | 5 | 15 | Geography | None | HS",
		"subject": "Geography",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: The United States Census Bureau defines this region as all of the former Confederacy plus Kentucky, West Virginia, Delaware, and Maryland. For 10 points each: [10] Name this region of the United States sometimes referred to as Dixie.",
		"answers": [
			"the",
			"South",
			"equivalents",
			"10",
			"This",
			"Texas",
			"metropolitan",
			"region",
			"an",
			"American",
			"Airlines",
			"hub",
			"largest",
			"in"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Crimean peninsula[10] This city on the Crimean peninsula was once home to the Soviet Black Sea fleet and is currently leased by the Russian navy.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "James |2013 | 6 | 3 | Geography | None | HS",
		"subject": "Geography",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: This European peninsula is the homeland of its namesake Tatars who were expelled by the Stalin government. For 10 points each: [10] Name this southern Ukranian peninsula bounded by the Black Sea to the south and the Sea of Azov to the east.",
		"answers": [
			"Crimean",
			"peninsula",
			"10",
			"This",
			"city",
			"was",
			"once",
			"home",
			"to",
			"Soviet",
			"Black",
			"Sea",
			"fleet",
			"and",
			"currently",
			"leased",
			"by",
			"Russian",
			"navy"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Ieoh Ming Pei[10] Pei also designed glass pyramids for the entrance to this landmark art museum located in Paris. The Mona Lisa's eyes supposedly follow the viewer around while viewing her in this museum.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "James |2013 | 6 | 10 | Geography | None | HS",
		"subject": "Geography",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: In 2012, a long time goal of playing Tetris with the windows of this man's Green Building at MIT was achieved. For 10 points each: [10] Name this Chinese-American architect who used part of a glass pyramid in designing the Rock and Roll Hall of Fame.",
		"answers": [
			"Ieoh",
			"Ming",
			"Pei",
			"10",
			"also",
			"designed",
			"glass",
			"pyramids",
			"for",
			"entrance",
			"to",
			"this",
			"landmark",
			"art",
			"museum",
			"located",
			"in",
			"Paris",
			"The",
			"Mona",
			"Lisa's",
			"eyes",
			"supposedly",
			"follow",
			"viewer",
			"around",
			"while",
			"viewing",
			"her"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Saint Petersburg[10] This city, the eastern terminus of the Trans-Siberian railway, is the largest Russian city on the Pacific Ocean.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "James |2013 | 7 | 9 | Geography | None | HS",
		"subject": "Geography",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: Russia, the largest nation in the world, also has some pretty big cities. For 10 points each: [10] This city, the second largest in Russia, was formerly known as Leningrad and Petrograd and was the capital before Moscow.",
		"answers": [
			"Saint",
			"Petersburg",
			"10",
			"This",
			"city",
			"eastern",
			"terminus",
			"Trans-Siberian",
			"railway",
			"largest",
			"Russian",
			"Pacific",
			"Ocean"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Olympus Mons[10] Olympus Mons is a volcano on this red planet that is also the site of the Valles Marineris.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "James |2013 | 8 | 8 | Geography | None | HS",
		"subject": "Geography",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: This feature formed during the Amazonian period. For 10 points each: [10] Name this shield volcano that was until 2011 known as the tallest mountain base-to-height in the Solar System.",
		"answers": [
			"Olympus",
			"Mons",
			"10",
			"volcano",
			"this",
			"red",
			"planet",
			"that",
			"also",
			"site",
			"Valles",
			"Marineris"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Tokyo [10] This island of Japan is home to Tokyo, Kobe, Hiroshima, and Sendai. It is the second most populous island in the world.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "James |2013 | 8 | 11 | Geography | None | HS",
		"subject": "Geography",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: This city was originally known as Edo. For 10 points each:  [10] Name this capital city of Japan. ",
		"answers": [
			"Tokyo",
			"10",
			"This",
			"island",
			"Japan",
			"home",
			"to",
			"Kobe",
			"Hiroshima",
			"and",
			"Sendai",
			"It",
			"second",
			"most",
			"populous",
			"in",
			"world"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Tokyo [10] This island of Japan is home to Tokyo, Kobe, Hiroshima, and Sendai. It is the second most populous island in the world.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "James |2013 | 8 | 11 | Geography | None | HS",
		"subject": "Geography",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: This city was originally known as Edo. For 10 points each:  [10] Name this capital city of Japan. ",
		"answers": [
			"Tokyo",
			"10",
			"This",
			"island",
			"Japan",
			"home",
			"to",
			"Kobe",
			"Hiroshima",
			"and",
			"Sendai",
			"It",
			"second",
			"most",
			"populous",
			"in",
			"world"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Alaska[10] This river, the longest in Alaska, originates in British Columbia and flows into the Bering Sea. A Canadian territory was named after this river.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "James |2013 | 9 | 1 | Geography | None | HS",
		"subject": "Geography",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: 1. This is the largest of the 50 United States. For 10 points each: [10] Name this home of the Brooks Range and the only state that has a shore on the Arctic Ocean. It is bordered by Canada on the east",
		"answers": [
			"Alaska",
			"10",
			"This",
			"river",
			"longest",
			"in",
			"originates",
			"British",
			"Columbia",
			"and",
			"flows",
			"into",
			"Bering",
			"Sea",
			"A",
			"Canadian",
			"territory",
			"was",
			"named",
			"after",
			"this"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Alberta[10] This river flows from Jasper National Park to a lake of the same name on Alberta's border with Saskatchewan, where it joins with the Peace River to form the Slave River. Its namesake oil sands are also located in Alberta.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "LIST (Ladue Invitational Spring Tournament) |2013 | 1 | 8 | Geography | None | HS",
		"subject": "Geography",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10] Name this westernmost of Canada's Prairie provinces which contains cities such as Edmonton and Calgary.",
		"answers": [
			"Alberta",
			"10",
			"This",
			"river",
			"flows",
			"from",
			"Jasper",
			"National",
			"Park",
			"to",
			"lake",
			"same",
			"name",
			"Alberta's",
			"border",
			"with",
			"Saskatchewan",
			"where",
			"joins",
			"Peace",
			"River",
			"form",
			"Slave",
			"Its",
			"namesake",
			"oil",
			"sands",
			"are",
			"also",
			"located",
			"in"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "lochs [accept Loch Eriboll or Loch Ness][10] Loch Eriboll is connected to the Pentland one of these inlets. The Solway one was the original western terminus of Hadrian's Wall.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "PACE |2013 | 3 | 3 | Geography | None | HS",
		"subject": "Geography",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: Give these Scottish geographic terms, for 10 points each: [10] Eriboll is a sea-inlet example of these features; the better-known freshwater ones include Ness, the supposed home of a legendary monster. ",
		"answers": [
			"lochs",
			"Loch",
			"Eriboll",
			"Ness",
			"10",
			"connected",
			"to",
			"Pentland",
			"one",
			"these",
			"inlets",
			"The",
			"Solway",
			"was",
			"original",
			"western",
			"terminus",
			"Hadrian's",
			"Wall"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Mount Rainier[10]  This other stratovolcano in the Cascade Range is famous for its 1980 eruption, the most destructive volcanic event in U.S. history which also formed this mountain's Crater Glacier.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2013 | Round01.docx | 19 | Geography |  | HS",
		"subject": "Geography",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  This stratovolcano in Washington State is the most topographically prominent mountain in the contiguous United States. Its highest summit is known as Columbia Crest.",
		"answers": [
			"Mount",
			"Rainier",
			"10",
			"This",
			"other",
			"stratovolcano",
			"in",
			"Cascade",
			"Range",
			"famous",
			"for",
			"its",
			"1980",
			"eruption",
			"most",
			"destructive",
			"volcanic",
			"event",
			"U",
			"S",
			"history",
			"which",
			"also",
			"formed",
			"this",
			"mountain's",
			"Crater",
			"Glacier"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Sydney[10]  Sydney is the capital of this state of Australia, bordered to the south by Victoria and to the west by South Australia. Other cities in this state include Wollongong and Newcastle, and it contains Mount Kosciuszko.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2013 | Round02.docx | 13 | Geography |  | HS",
		"subject": "Geography",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Name this largest city of Australia that contains Warragamba Dam as well as an architecturally significant Opera House on Bennelong Point.",
		"answers": [
			"Sydney",
			"10",
			"capital",
			"this",
			"state",
			"Australia",
			"bordered",
			"to",
			"south",
			"by",
			"Victoria",
			"and",
			"west",
			"South",
			"Other",
			"cities",
			"in",
			"include",
			"Wollongong",
			"Newcastle",
			"contains",
			"Mount",
			"Kosciuszko"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Republic of Poland[10]  This capital of Poland sits on the Vistula and contains a statue of its coat of arms, a mermaid brandishing a sword, in its Old Town Market Place.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2013 | Round03.docx | 15 | Geography |  | HS",
		"subject": "Geography",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Name this European nation which houses the White Stork Synagogue in Wroclaw, the capital of Lower Silesian Voivodeship. Other cities on the Oder in this country include a town named Police.",
		"answers": [
			"Republic",
			"Poland",
			"10",
			"This",
			"capital",
			"sits",
			"Vistula",
			"and",
			"contains",
			"statue",
			"its",
			"coat",
			"arms",
			"mermaid",
			"brandishing",
			"sword",
			"in",
			"Old",
			"Town",
			"Market",
			"Place"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Rio Grande [or Rio Bravo del Norte][10]  Mexico also features this long, narrow peninsula in its northwest. In this peninsula's north are the cities of Mexicali and Tijuana, while the Sierra de la Laguna range can be found in its south.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2013 | Round04.docx | 16 | Geography |  | HS",
		"subject": "Geography",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Name this river whose mouth is in Matamoros, a city in the state of Tamaulipas. It also serves as the southern border for Terrell and Maverick Counties.",
		"answers": [
			"Rio",
			"Grande",
			"Bravo",
			"del",
			"Norte",
			"10",
			"Mexico",
			"also",
			"features",
			"this",
			"long",
			"narrow",
			"peninsula",
			"in",
			"its",
			"northwest",
			"In",
			"peninsula's",
			"north",
			"are",
			"cities",
			"Mexicali",
			"and",
			"Tijuana",
			"while",
			"Sierra",
			"de",
			"la",
			"Laguna",
			"range",
			"can",
			"be",
			"found",
			"south"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Sea of Japan [or East Sea][10]  La Perouse Strait separates Sakhalin from this northernmost Japanese island famous for its Ainu population. Its city of Hakodate is the capital of Oshima Subprefecture.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2013 | Round05.docx | 5 | Geography |  | HS",
		"subject": "Geography",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Name this body of water bordered to the north by Russian coastal cities like Vladivostok and to the west by the Korean peninsula. This body contains Moneron Island owned by Sakhalin, known for its sea lions.",
		"answers": [
			"Sea",
			"Japan",
			"East",
			"10",
			"La",
			"Perouse",
			"Strait",
			"separates",
			"Sakhalin",
			"from",
			"this",
			"northernmost",
			"Japanese",
			"island",
			"famous",
			"for",
			"its",
			"Ainu",
			"population",
			"Its",
			"city",
			"Hakodate",
			"capital",
			"Oshima",
			"Subprefecture"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Antarctica[10]  This sea, one of two major Antarctic bays, is notoriously perilous, being the site of the freezing of Ernest Shackleton's ship Endurance. Its namesake seal can be found on the Antarctic Peninsula.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2013 | Round06.docx | 6 | Geography |  | HS",
		"subject": "Geography",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Name this continent, the windiest and driest continent on average, which has its highest point at Vinson Massif in the Ellsworth Mountains.",
		"answers": [
			"Antarctica",
			"10",
			"This",
			"sea",
			"one",
			"two",
			"major",
			"Antarctic",
			"bays"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Seattle[10]  Seattle, as well as Tacoma and Kitsap Peninsula, is located on this body of water. Admiralty Inlet connects this body of water to the Strait of Juan de Fuca, which opens into the Pacific Ocean.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2013 | Round07.docx | 14 | Geography |  | HS",
		"subject": "Geography",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Name this large coastal city in Washington State whose Century 21 Exposition in 1962 saw the construction of the Space Needle, which is a short walk from the Experience Music Project.",
		"answers": [
			"Seattle",
			"10",
			"as",
			"well",
			"Tacoma",
			"and",
			"Kitsap",
			"Peninsula",
			"located",
			"this",
			"body",
			"water",
			"Admiralty",
			"Inlet",
			"connects",
			"to",
			"Strait",
			"Juan",
			"de",
			"Fuca",
			"which",
			"opens",
			"into",
			"Pacific",
			"Ocean"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Niagara Falls[10]  This highest uninterrupted waterfall is located in Canaima National Park in Venezuela. It is named for the American aviator who discovered it upon crashing his monoplane onto Auyantepui.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2013 | Round08.docx | 1 | Geography |  | HS",
		"subject": "Geography",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  These falls actually consist of three waterfalls, two in New York State and Horseshoe Falls in Ontario, Canada. Its namesake river connects Lake Ontario and Lake Erie.",
		"answers": [
			"Niagara",
			"Falls",
			"10",
			"This",
			"highest",
			"uninterrupted",
			"waterfall",
			"located",
			"in",
			"Canaima",
			"National",
			"Park",
			"Venezuela",
			"It",
			"named",
			"for",
			"American",
			"aviator",
			"who",
			"discovered",
			"upon",
			"crashing",
			"his",
			"monoplane",
			"onto",
			"Auyantepui"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Republic of South Africa[10]  In South Africa's north is this desert, which primarily covers Botswana and Namibia. The Okavango River flows through this desert, home to the Dragon's Breath Cave, which contains a huge underground lake.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2013 | Round09.docx | 11 | Geography |  | HS",
		"subject": "Geography",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Name this country whose highest point, Mafadi, is located in the Drakensberg range. This polity recognizes distinct executive, judicial, and legislative capital cities.",
		"answers": [
			"Republic",
			"South",
			"Africa",
			"10",
			"In",
			"Africa's",
			"north",
			"this",
			"desert",
			"which",
			"primarily",
			"covers",
			"Botswana",
			"and",
			"Namibia",
			"The",
			"Okavango",
			"River",
			"flows",
			"through",
			"home",
			"to",
			"Dragon's",
			"Breath",
			"Cave",
			"contains",
			"huge",
			"underground",
			"lake"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Republic of Madagascar[10]  This archipelago owned by Chile and Argentina is separated from the rest of South America by the Strait of Magellan. Its southernmost island is Cape Horn, and it also includes a Staten Island.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2013 | Round10.docx | 16 | Geography |  | HS",
		"subject": "Geography",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  This Indian Ocean island nation is located off the southeastern coast of Africa. Its capital of Antananarivo is located in the Analamanga region.",
		"answers": [
			"Republic",
			"Madagascar",
			"10",
			"This",
			"archipelago",
			"owned",
			"by",
			"Chile",
			"and",
			"Argentina",
			"separated",
			"from",
			"rest",
			"South",
			"America",
			"Strait",
			"Magellan",
			"Its",
			"southernmost",
			"island",
			"Cape",
			"Horn",
			"also",
			"includes",
			"Staten",
			"Island"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Yangtze River [or Chang Jiang][10]  This structure built on the Yangtze River is the largest hydroelectric power station in the world. Completed in 2012, this controversial dam is located in Yichang, in the Hubei province.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2013 | Round11.docx | 19 | Geography |  | HS",
		"subject": "Geography",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  This river begins at a glacier on Geladandong Peak before flowing east. One of its headwaters, the Golden Sands River, features the very deep Tiger Leaping Gorge.",
		"answers": [
			"Yangtze",
			"River",
			"Chang",
			"Jiang",
			"10",
			"This",
			"structure",
			"built",
			"largest",
			"hydroelectric",
			"power",
			"station",
			"in",
			"world",
			"Completed",
			"2012",
			"this",
			"controversial",
			"dam",
			"located",
			"Yichang",
			"Hubei",
			"province"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Andes Mountains[10]  The Andes pass through this country with both a constitutional capital and a departmental capital, which is the highest capital city in the world. This landlocked nation contains Santa Cruz and much of the Altiplano.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2013 | Round12.docx | 1 | Geography |  | HS",
		"subject": "Geography",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Name this South American mountain range, which reaches as far north as Merida in Venezuela to Mount Aconcagua in Argentina.",
		"answers": [
			"Andes",
			"Mountains",
			"10",
			"The",
			"pass",
			"through",
			"this",
			"country",
			"with",
			"both",
			"constitutional",
			"capital",
			"and",
			"departmental",
			"which",
			"highest",
			"city",
			"in",
			"world",
			"This",
			"landlocked",
			"nation",
			"contains",
			"Santa",
			"Cruz",
			"much",
			"Altiplano"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Zambezi River[10]  The Zambezi flows through the eastern portion of this nation whose capital is Luanda. This former Portuguese colony now has a province named Zaire, which borders the Democratic Republic of the Congo.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2013 | Round13.docx | 20 | Geography |  | HS",
		"subject": "Geography",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  The Kabompo and Lungwebungu Rivers are major tributaries of this river. It also flows along the eastern border of Namibia and the northern border of Botswana after originating in Zambia.",
		"answers": [
			"Zambezi",
			"River",
			"10",
			"The",
			"flows",
			"through",
			"eastern",
			"portion",
			"this",
			"nation",
			"whose",
			"capital",
			"Luanda",
			"This",
			"former",
			"Portuguese",
			"colony",
			"now",
			"has",
			"province",
			"named",
			"Zaire",
			"which",
			"borders",
			"Democratic",
			"Republic",
			"Congo"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Naples [or Napoli][10]  We got on a cruise ship and began sailing due west, ending up in this sea on the Mediterranean. This sea is connected to the Ligurian Sea by the Corsica Channel.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2013 | Round14.docx | 8 | Geography |  | HS",
		"subject": "Geography",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  We begin in this \"new city\" sandwiched between the Phlegraean Fields and Mount Vesuvius, the capital of the region of Campania. It's essential to visit the Palace of Caserta and the huge square, Piazza del Plebiscito.",
		"answers": [
			"Naples",
			"Napoli",
			"10",
			"We",
			"got",
			"cruise",
			"ship",
			"and",
			"began",
			"sailing",
			"due",
			"west",
			"ending",
			"up",
			"in",
			"this",
			"sea",
			"Mediterranean",
			"This",
			"connected",
			"to",
			"Ligurian",
			"Sea",
			"by",
			"Corsica",
			"Channel"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Republic of Guatemala[10]  This mountain range dividing Europe and Asia lies west of Yekaterinburg. It begins at the Kara Sea and ends at the Kazakh Steppes. Its highest point is Mount Narodnaya.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2013 | Round15.docx | 14 | Geography |  | HS",
		"subject": "Geography",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Along with Belize, this country is the border between North America and South America. Hurricanes Mitch and Stan occurred here, and its cities include Petapa, Mixco, and Villa Nueva.",
		"answers": [
			"Republic",
			"Guatemala",
			"10",
			"This",
			"mountain",
			"range",
			"dividing",
			"Europe",
			"and",
			"Asia",
			"lies",
			"west",
			"Yekaterinburg",
			"It",
			"begins",
			"at",
			"Kara",
			"Sea",
			"ends",
			"Kazakh",
			"Steppes",
			"Its",
			"highest",
			"point",
			"Mount",
			"Narodnaya"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Alberta[10]  This river flows from Jasper National Park to a lake of the same name on Alberta's border with Saskatchewan, where it joins with the Peace River to form the Slave River. Its namesake oil sands are also located in Alberta.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "LIST (Ladue Invitational Spring Tournament) |2012 | LISTIII_Round01.docx | 8 | Geography |  | HS",
		"subject": "Geography",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Name this westernmost of Canada's Prairie provinces which contains cities such as Edmonton and Calgary.",
		"answers": [
			"Alberta",
			"10",
			"This",
			"river",
			"flows",
			"from",
			"Jasper",
			"National",
			"Park",
			"to",
			"lake",
			"same",
			"name",
			"Alberta's",
			"border",
			"with",
			"Saskatchewan",
			"where",
			"joins",
			"Peace",
			"River",
			"form",
			"Slave",
			"Its",
			"namesake",
			"oil",
			"sands",
			"are",
			"also",
			"located",
			"in"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Idaho[10]  This river rises in Yellowstone National Park and receives the Salmon and Clearwater Rivers in Idaho before passing into Washington and eventually flowing into the Columbia River.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "LIST (Ladue Invitational Spring Tournament) |2012 | LISTIII_Round02.docx | 1 | Geography |  | HS",
		"subject": "Geography",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Name this state which contains cities such as Pocatello, Coeur d'Alene (\"KORR duh-LAYN\"), and Boise.",
		"answers": [
			"Idaho",
			"10",
			"This",
			"river",
			"rises",
			"in",
			"Yellowstone",
			"National",
			"Park",
			"and",
			"receives",
			"Salmon",
			"Clearwater",
			"Rivers",
			"passing",
			"into",
			"Washington",
			"eventually",
			"flowing",
			"Columbia",
			"River"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Kingdom of Spain (or Reino de Espana)[10]  This longest river on the Iberian Peninsula rises in the Meseta Central and flows past Toledo before emptying into the Atlantic at Lisbon.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "LIST (Ladue Invitational Spring Tournament) |2012 | LISTIII_Round03.docx | 17 | Geography |  | HS",
		"subject": "Geography",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Name this country with cities such as Cadiz, Asturias, and Valladolid which lies across the Strait of Gibraltar from Morocco.",
		"answers": [
			"Kingdom",
			"Spain",
			"Reino",
			"de",
			"Espana",
			"10",
			"This",
			"longest",
			"river",
			"Iberian",
			"Peninsula",
			"rises",
			"in",
			"Meseta",
			"Central",
			"and",
			"flows",
			"past",
			"Toledo",
			"emptying",
			"into",
			"Atlantic",
			"at",
			"Lisbon"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Borneo[10]  Indonesia also contains this island that contains the cities of Banda Aceh, Palembang, and Medan. It lies across the Sunda Strait from Java and across the Strait of Malacca from the Malay Peninsula.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "LIST (Ladue Invitational Spring Tournament) |2012 | LISTIII_Round04.docx | 17 | Geography |  | HS",
		"subject": "Geography",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Name this third largest island in the world, which is shared between Brunei, Malaysia, and Indonesia.",
		"answers": [
			"Borneo",
			"10",
			"Indonesia",
			"also",
			"contains",
			"this",
			"island",
			"that",
			"cities",
			"Banda",
			"Aceh",
			"Palembang",
			"and",
			"Medan",
			"It",
			"lies",
			"across",
			"Sunda",
			"Strait",
			"from",
			"Java",
			"Malacca",
			"Malay",
			"Peninsula"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Republic of Namibia[10]  This desert, home to the Bushmen and the Makgadikgadi salt pan, is shared among Namibia, South Africa, and Botswana.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "LIST (Ladue Invitational Spring Tournament) |2012 | LISTIII_Round05.docx | 3 | Geography |  | HS",
		"subject": "Geography",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Name this country which contains Walvis Bay and the Skeleton Coast with capital at Windhoek. Its southern border is formed by the Orange River.",
		"answers": [
			"Republic",
			"Namibia",
			"10",
			"This",
			"desert",
			"home",
			"to",
			"Bushmen",
			"and",
			"Makgadikgadi",
			"salt",
			"pan",
			"shared",
			"among",
			"South",
			"Africa",
			"Botswana"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "New Mexico[10]  This national park lies in southeastern New Mexico and features the Big Room, the third largest cave chamber in North America.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "LIST (Ladue Invitational Spring Tournament) |2012 | LISTIII_Round06.docx | 20 | Geography |  | HS",
		"subject": "Geography",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Name this state bisected by the Rio Grande which contains White Sands National Monument and cities like Alamogordo, Las Cruces, Albuquerque, and Santa Fe.",
		"answers": [
			"New",
			"Mexico",
			"10",
			"This",
			"national",
			"park",
			"lies",
			"in",
			"southeastern",
			"and",
			"features",
			"Big",
			"Room",
			"third",
			"largest",
			"cave",
			"chamber",
			"North",
			"America"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Munich (or Munchen)[10]  Before joining the Danube at Belgrade, the Sava flows through the capital of this country that contains the Istrian Peninsula and the cities of Rijeka and Dubrovnik.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "LIST (Ladue Invitational Spring Tournament) |2012 | LISTIII_Round07.docx | 7 | Geography |  | HS",
		"subject": "Geography",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Before joining the Danube, the Isar flows through this Oktoberfest-celebrating capital city of Bavaria.",
		"answers": [
			"Munich",
			"Munchen",
			"10",
			"Before",
			"joining",
			"Danube",
			"at",
			"Belgrade",
			"Sava",
			"flows",
			"through",
			"capital",
			"this",
			"country",
			"that",
			"contains",
			"Istrian",
			"Peninsula",
			"and",
			"cities",
			"Rijeka",
			"Dubrovnik"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Republic of Nicaragua[10]  This country contains the Great Blue Hole as well as a namesake barrier reef that is the second longest in the world. It is the only officially English-speaking country in Central America and the only one not to border the Pacific Ocean.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "LIST (Ladue Invitational Spring Tournament) |2012 | LISTIII_Round08.docx | 11 | Geography |  | HS",
		"subject": "Geography",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  This country that lies at the southern end of the Gulf of Fonseca and contains the largest lake in Central America as well as a lake named after its capital, Managua.",
		"answers": [
			"Republic",
			"Nicaragua",
			"10",
			"This",
			"country",
			"contains",
			"Great",
			"Blue",
			"Hole",
			"as",
			"well",
			"namesake",
			"barrier",
			"reef",
			"that",
			"second",
			"longest",
			"in",
			"world",
			"It",
			"only",
			"officially",
			"English-speaking",
			"Central",
			"America",
			"and",
			"one"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Toronto[10]  Queen Charlotte Island is a part of this Canadian province, which also features the Fraser River and the Hecate Strait. Its capital is Victoria and its largest city lies across the border from the state of Washington.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "LIST (Ladue Invitational Spring Tournament) |2012 | LISTIII_Round09.docx | 7 | Geography |  | HS",
		"subject": "Geography",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  This provincial capital of Ontario lies on Lake Ontario. The most recognizable feature of this largest city in Canada is its 1800-foot tall CN Tower.",
		"answers": [
			"Toronto",
			"10",
			"Queen",
			"Charlotte",
			"Island",
			"part",
			"this",
			"Canadian",
			"province",
			"which",
			"also",
			"features",
			"Fraser",
			"River",
			"and",
			"Hecate",
			"Strait",
			"Its",
			"capital",
			"Victoria",
			"its",
			"largest",
			"city",
			"lies",
			"across",
			"border",
			"from",
			"state",
			"Washington"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Minnesota[10]  This river forms the border between Minnesota and North Dakota. Another river of the same name forms the border between Oklahoma and Texas and flows into the Mississippi River in Louisiana.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "LIST (Ladue Invitational Spring Tournament) |2012 | LISTIII_Round10.docx | 1 | Geography |  | HS",
		"subject": "Geography",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Name this state which contains Lake Itasca as well as the cities of Duluth, St. Paul, and Minneapolis.",
		"answers": [
			"Minnesota",
			"10",
			"This",
			"river",
			"forms",
			"border",
			"between",
			"and",
			"North",
			"Dakota"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Santiago (accept but do not reveal Santiago de Chile)[10]  Santiago is the capital of this long, narrow country which contains the western half of Tierra del Fuego in its south and the Atacama Desert in its north.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "LIST (Ladue Invitational Spring Tournament) |2012 | LISTIII_Round11.docx | 8 | Geography |  | HS",
		"subject": "Geography",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Name this South American capital city which lies 60 miles southwest of Aconcagua and 70 miles southeast of the port of Valparaiso.",
		"answers": [
			"Santiago",
			"but"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Scotland (or Alba)[10]  Scotland controls the Shetland Islands, the Orkney Islands, and this archipelago lying off the western coast of Scotland which contains the Isle of Lewis and the Isle of Skye.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "LIST (Ladue Invitational Spring Tournament) |2012 | LISTIII_Round12.docx | 21 | Geography |  | HS",
		"subject": "Geography",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Name this country which contains the Firth of Forth and the Firth of Clyde as well as cities such as Aberdeen, Glasgow, and its capital Edinburgh, which lies north of England.",
		"answers": [
			"Scotland",
			"Alba",
			"10",
			"controls",
			"Shetland",
			"Islands",
			"Orkney",
			"and",
			"this",
			"archipelago",
			"lying",
			"off",
			"western",
			"coast",
			"which",
			"contains",
			"Isle",
			"Lewis",
			"Skye"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "New Guinea (or Papua Island; do not accept \"Papua New Guinea\")[10]  This strait, which connects the Arafura Sea to the Coral Sea, separates New Guinea from the Cape York Peninsula.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "LIST (Ladue Invitational Spring Tournament) |2012 | LISTIII_Round13.docx | 11 | Geography |  | HS",
		"subject": "Geography",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Name this large island, the western portion of which contains Puncak Jaya and is controlled by Indonesia, and the eastern portion of which contains a namesake country with capital at Port Moresby.",
		"answers": [
			"New",
			"Guinea",
			"Papua",
			"Island"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Nevada[10]  New Orleans lies in between the Mississippi River and this second largest saltwater lake in the United States.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "LIST (Ladue Invitational Spring Tournament) |2012 | LISTIII_Round14.docx | 18 | Geography |  | HS",
		"subject": "Geography",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Lake Tahoe lies on the border between California and this state, which also contains Pyramid Lake and cities such as Reno and Carson City.",
		"answers": [
			"Nevada",
			"10",
			"New",
			"Orleans",
			"lies",
			"in",
			"between",
			"Mississippi",
			"River",
			"and",
			"this",
			"second",
			"largest",
			"saltwater",
			"lake",
			"United",
			"States"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Islamic Republic of Afghanistan[10]  Tirich Mir is the highest point in this mountain range which dominates central and northeastern Afghanistan.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "LIST (Ladue Invitational Spring Tournament) |2012 | LISTIII_Round15.docx | 11 | Geography |  | HS",
		"subject": "Geography",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Name this landlocked country in which the Helmand River drains into the Sistan Basin. Its cities include Herat, Kandahar, and its capital, Kabul.",
		"answers": [
			"Islamic",
			"Republic",
			"Afghanistan",
			"10",
			"Tirich",
			"Mir",
			"highest",
			"point",
			"in",
			"this",
			"mountain",
			"range",
			"which",
			"dominates",
			"central",
			"and",
			"northeastern"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Republic of Djibouti[10]  The Bab-el-Mandeb connects the Gulf of Aden to this sea, which is in turn connected to the Mediterranean Sea by the Suez Canal.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "LIST (Ladue Invitational Spring Tournament) |2012 | LISTIII_Round16.docx | 19 | Geography |  | HS",
		"subject": "Geography",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Name this small country that lies across the Bab-el-Mandeb from Yemen.",
		"answers": [
			"Republic",
			"Djibouti",
			"10",
			"The",
			"Bab-el-Mandeb",
			"connects",
			"Gulf",
			"Aden",
			"to",
			"this",
			"sea",
			"which",
			"in",
			"turn",
			"connected",
			"Mediterranean",
			"Sea",
			"by",
			"Suez",
			"Canal"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Johannesburg [or Egoli][10] This city near Johannesburg is the administrative capital of South Africa, as opposed to the other two judicial  and legislative capitals. It is named after a leader of the Voortrekkers.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2012 | 4 | 2 | Geography | None | HS",
		"subject": "Geography",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: It is the world's largest city not located on a river or body of water. For 10 points each: [10] Name this city containing the impoverished Soweto area; it is the largest city in South Africa.",
		"answers": [
			"Johannesburg",
			"Egoli",
			"10",
			"This",
			"city",
			"near",
			"administrative",
			"capital",
			"South",
			"Africa",
			"as",
			"opposed",
			"to",
			"other",
			"two",
			"judicial",
			"and",
			"legislative",
			"capitals",
			"It",
			"named",
			"after",
			"leader",
			"Voortrekkers"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Anchorage[10] This western Alaskan city was a gold mining boom town, and is the end point of the Iditarod Trail Sled Dog Race.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "BHSAT |2011 | 1 | 16 | Geography | None | HS",
		"subject": "Geography",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: America's largest state is also one of its least populated. For 10 points each: [10] This is Alaska's largest city, home to over half its population.",
		"answers": [
			"Anchorage",
			"10",
			"This",
			"western",
			"Alaskan",
			"city",
			"was",
			"gold",
			"mining",
			"boom",
			"town",
			"and",
			"end",
			"point",
			"Iditarod",
			"Trail",
			"Sled",
			"Dog",
			"Race"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Philippines[10] This city adjacent to the capital Manila is the largest city in the Philippines.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "BHSAT |2011 | 2 | 5 | Geography | None | HS",
		"subject": "Geography",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: Consisting of over 7,000 islands, this country featured a large settlement on a mountainous landfill in Payatas.. For 10 points each: [10] Name this country, separated from Taiwan by the Luzon Strait and from Indonesia by the Sulu Sea. Its capital city is Manila.",
		"answers": [
			"Philippines",
			"10",
			"This",
			"city",
			"adjacent",
			"to",
			"capital",
			"Manila",
			"largest",
			"in"
		]
	}
]